CHRYSOSTOMOS (MAKIS) MILAS



CONTACT



Tranekærvej 59, 8240 Risskov, Denmark



+4550333063



makoulism@hotmail.com

SKILLS

- Great flair for IT
- High interest and curiosity on new technologies
- Excellent verbal, written, analytical and communication skills, literacy and numeracy
- Ability to work without supervision and on own initiative
- High adaptability in professional environment
- Time and project management
- Dedication to set goals
- Natural team player
- European driving license Class B

TECHNOLOGIES

- Experience working with languages such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and PHP7, libraries (jQuery), frameworks (Vue.js, Bootstrap 4.5, Express.js)
- Node.js, MongoDB, GoormIDE, Mongoose, npm, Firebase, Figma, Git, Bitbucket, Slack, Jira, VS-Code
- WRF (Weather Research & Forecasting) model, GrADS, Matlab and Fortran
- Microsoft OfficeTM tools (WordTM, ExcelTM and PowerPointTM)
- Excellence on tailored production software for previous position

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

- Leadership Skills
- Communication Skills
- Coaching Skills
- Web development courses on Udemy

SUMMARY

I'm a self-starter on web development with a M.Sc. degree and diverse background and I have recently finished my web development internship at DigitalGuest. At this position I was developing with Vue.js, HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript and with the use of Git, npm, Bitbucket and Jira I worked in an agile way to implement new functionalities and UI updates on the platform. I have also deployed a Heroku app (RESTfull routing) whilst following online courses on web development. I'm highly adaptable, passionate about succeeding in the field and goal oriented. I have moved to Aarhus from the UK with my partner ready to look for my next professional challenge.

Chrysostomos (Makis) Milas | LinkedIn Makis Milas (online-portfolio-a916d.web.app) GreekCamps (murmuring-meadow-93919.herokuapp.com)

WORK EXPERIENCE

November 2020 to January 2021

Developer Intern

DigitalGuest, Aarhus, Denmark

- UI updates on the platform (HTML, CSS, Ant-design, FlexBox, BEM)
- Building new features (Vue.is, Firebase, Git)
- Close collaboration with UI/UX experts, internal and external partners
- Following SCRUM and agile methodologies to collaborate with the rest of the development team
- QA and bug fixes on the platform

October 2018 to April 2020

Assistant Production Manager

Caffé Nero Roastery, London, United Kingdom

- Control room operator
- Organizing and optimizing daily production plan, overseeing that short and long term production is carried out to the required standards
- Managing the team of *Assistants to the production*, throughout the day
- Ensuring all lines of production run according to the BRC (British Retail Consortium) regulations including final product and packaging
- Having a methodical, accurate "Mechanical" attitude to enable monitoring all production machinery

November 2016 to September 2018

Assistant Store Manager

Caffé Nero Store, London, United Kingdom

Responsible for running the shop, serving customers and

LANGUAGES

- Greek (native)
- English (fluent)
- Danish (A1)
- French (basic)

INTERESTS

- Travelling abroad
- Sports (swimming, football)
- Music (concerts of different styles)
- Computer Games
- Languages
- Movies

REFERENCES

Available on request

- keeping high hygiene standards
- Assigned to run every shift when on duty and to deal with store-related matters

September 2014 to February 2015

Junior PHP Developer (Internship)

Meteovista, Zeist, The Netherlands

- Project organization, creation of the workflow and running all scripts
- Deal with strict deadlines in order to deliver the final product successfully on time
- Give the scientific perspective on the ongoing application
- Write the PHP code under the Object Oriented Paradigm in the most efficient and clear way for further development
- Internship project: Derivation of wind field and forecast rain field out of a series of radar images. Performed alongside with an operational meteorologist as supervisor using PHP (OOP)

EDUCATION

March 2015

M.Sc. Climate Studies

Meteorology and Air Quality Department Wageningen University, The Netherlands

- Demonstration of an in-depth theoretical and practical knowledge of natural and computer sciences
- Demonstration of considerable ability on project management, task prioritization and good time management
- M.Sc. Thesis: Dynamic Coupling of Sudden Stratospheric Warmings with Tropospheric Blockings. Performed with FORTRAN alongside with GrADS
- Academic Consultancy Training (ACT) project against climate change and mitigation/adaptation strategies to it, conducted for a real client

November 2011

B.Sc. Physics

Department of Physics of Atmosphere and Environment Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece

- Educated in a wide spectrum of natural sciences
- Participated in numerous laboratory projects
- Became able to work and manipulate large data sets

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- January 2013 January 2014: Member of the Educational Committee (OpCie) of the M.Sc. Programme Climate Studies (targeted to improve the ranking of the M.Sc. and to attract more students to it through meetings and discussions with the head of the department, professors, study advisor, secretary and a representation of students)
- July 2007: Volunteer at 1st Southeastern European Countries Games in Thessaloniki, Greece
- July 2015 March 2016: Fulfilling the mandatory military services in Greece